[{"answer": "I feel very strongly that marriage is between a man and a woman.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 3, "question": "Will this change America's mind?", "qSentId": 2}, {"answer": "Literally.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 13, "question": "Did I really?", "qSentId": 12}, {"answer": "I was -- I was sitting home alone.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 46, "question": "How did you personally feel?", "qSentId": 45}, {"answer": "Well, I mean the presidency above everything else is a bully pulpit.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 62, "question": "What do you think this will do to the debate in America?", "qSentId": 61}, {"answer": "No, it's a big --", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 70, "question": "I mean, does this not illustrate in my view the futility of a state system, where you can travel around America and you can be legally gay married here, not legally gay married there, legally gay married here?", "qSentId": 69}, {"answer": "I don't know whether it's going to help Mitt Romney come November.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 99, "question": "Does this make Barack Obama a flip-flopper and does that help Mitt Romney come November?", "qSentId": 98}, {"answer": "It's astonishing what President Obama did today.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 116, "question": "What is your reaction to what happened today?", "qSentId": 115}, {"answer": "OK.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 141, "question": "Now I want to ask this gentleman here, does he have a problem with that?", "qSentId": 140}, {"answer": "Look, I -- the gentleman brings up the golden rule.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 143, "question": "Well, do you have a problem with that?", "qSentId": 142}, {"answer": "And --", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 148, "question": "What about the Muths?", "qSentId": 147}, {"answer": "I find -- I find --", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 153, "question": "Do you have a problem with that, sir?", "qSentId": 152}, {"answer": "-- wanting to make the lifetime commitment of -- wanting to make the lifetime --", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 162, "question": "You discriminate then, don't you?", "qSentId": 161}, {"answer": "It's absolutely very simple.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 166, "question": "-- with two loving Americans getting married?", "qSentId": 165}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 181, "question": "Are these the kind of marriages that you prefer?", "qSentId": 180}, {"answer": "No, it's not just about love.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 184, "question": "To a gay couple that have been together 20 years?", "qSentId": 183}, {"answer": "Well, because, as I've tried to say to you, the social science evidence is on my side, not on your side.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 207, "question": "Why would it?", "qSentId": 206}, {"answer": "And I say to you -- excuse me.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 210, "question": "What is it?", "qSentId": 209}, {"answer": "Excuse me, Piers, look, Alan and Patricia Muth wanted to get married, they're brother and sister.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 212, "question": "What is the social science evidence?", "qSentId": 211}, {"answer": "No, we never talked about my views of gay people.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 217, "question": "Bill, let's just -- let's just get back to your views of gay people, all right?", "qSentId": 216}, {"answer": "Yes, of course.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 222, "question": "Have you got children?", "qSentId": 221}, {"answer": "OK.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 224, "question": "What kind of question is this?", "qSentId": 223}, {"answer": "I would love --", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 229, "question": "What would you do to them?", "qSentId": 228}, {"answer": "I would love them because you -- the Catholic Church teaches that all people, gay and straight, should be loved.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 231, "question": "What would you say to him?", "qSentId": 230}, {"answer": "I -- I am.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 251, "question": "So, Clay, you must be pretty happy that he reacted so quickly?", "qSentId": 250}, {"answer": "You know, it is a little bittersweet.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 257, "question": "How did you feel when you heard the news?", "qSentId": 256}, {"answer": "IKEN: I was worried about coming on here and looking foolish tonight and there's no way that I can now because the standard has dropped to the floor.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 272, "question": "You know, really?", "qSentId": 271}, {"answer": "Well, you know, in North Carolina --", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 277, "question": "I mean seriously?", "qSentId": 276}, {"answer": "You know, I think it was an evolution, much like it was for the president.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 314, "question": "I mean what's it been like?", "qSentId": 313}, {"answer": "If you were Mitt Romney, you might be thinking they were going to hammer me over flip-flopping, I've got him here.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 327, "question": "Pardon me?", "qSentId": 326}, {"answer": "It was shocking, especially when Proposition 8 was first on the ballot, because I felt -- I was just certain that it would never come to be, because we are California.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 394, "question": "How do you feel about that?", "qSentId": 393}, {"answer": "Well, I mean, it really seems to boil down to the definition of marriage.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 398, "question": "Why do you think the critics of this care so much?", "qSentId": 397}, {"answer": "Yeah, that --", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 419, "question": "I thought, what?", "qSentId": 418}, {"answer": "I hope so.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 429, "question": "Is it more ignorance than bigotry, do you think?", "qSentId": 428}, {"answer": "No.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 437, "question": "Were you a bit fed up with Vice President Biden when he quoted a rival show, \"Will & Grace\"?", "qSentId": 436}, {"answer": "I personally have not had that reaction.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 450, "question": "Do you still get that kind of reaction from anywhere that you go in your country?", "qSentId": 449}, {"answer": "He basically just affirmed what everyone thought anyway.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 478, "question": "What do you personally think of the president of your country sitting there and announcing momentously that he supports gay marriage?", "qSentId": 477}, {"answer": "I agreed with the president today.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 492, "question": "Did you agree with the president today?", "qSentId": 491}, {"answer": "I think Republicans need to embrace the issue.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 504, "question": "What do you think of the way the Republicans are now positioning this?", "qSentId": 503}, {"answer": "I think the youth were galvanized to take out their credit cards at least today.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 518, "question": "What do you think?", "qSentId": 517}, {"answer": "I'd say hindered.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 529, "question": "Let me start with you, Ben, yes or no?", "qSentId": 528}, {"answer": "Hindered.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 533, "question": "Dana?", "qSentId": 532}, {"answer": "Helped.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 540, "question": "Elise?", "qSentId": 539}, {"answer": "I think helped, no question, because Americans want their politicians to believe in themselves and in their communities.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 544, "question": "Hilary?", "qSentId": 543}, {"answer": "It gets better all the time.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 569, "question": "Lewis, how are you?", "qSentId": 568}, {"answer": "Well, you know, I don't know -- the gay couples I know have some of the longest relationships that I know.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 583, "question": "Why can't they?", "qSentId": 582}, {"answer": "Yes, I do.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 633, "question": "You have five kids, right?", "qSentId": 632}, {"answer": "Well, we would have a conversation about it.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 635, "question": "What would you do if one of them came home and said, dad, I'm gay?", "qSentId": 634}, {"answer": "Well, I certainly would like to see a bit more grit in terms of gay issues, in terms of LGBT issues.", "docId": "120509pmt", "aSentId": 638, "question": "If he gets re-elected, where do you want to see a bit more grit?", "qSentId": 637}]